Everyone's obsessed with automating work
with engineers. And the way you do it
best is to figure out where you need
human review. Let's say you have a
process that looks like this. Imagine
totally pre-AI where maybe you plan some
work and then you ship some work and
then maybe you review some work. And all
of these checkpoints, all of the moments
where you check the work, these are all
human. A lot of people's dream, I think,
is to have these all translated over to
AI at once. But for me, that doesn't
really make sense. On very large pieces
of work, you probably want to align with
the AI first. In other words, you want
to be involved at the initial planning
stage. That's what my skills like Grill
Me and Grill with Docs and Wayfinder all
do. And then you probably also want some
human review right at the end before you
ship it to production. However, there
are some situations where you don't need
that much human review at the end
because maybe it's just a refactor, just
an internal documentation rename. Maybe
the human can just align early on,
basically consider that the plan is
done, and then the AI can ship it all
the way to prod. That is good for some
cases. There are also some cases where
you can just specify the work that needs
doing in like a single prompt, not
bother really aligning with the AI, not
bother grilling, and just let it ship
through the process, and then just
review it before it goes live. That can
be really effective for very simple
changes, very small diffs, stuff that's
not going to make a big splash or a big
impact, you know, just
changing the color of a button or
changing the name of a title or
something. Even things like fix a small
bug here that's just a couple of lines
change, you should probably shift that
checkpoint to the right. And that's the
right language to use here. You shift
checkpoints left for big work, for stuff
you need to align on first, and you can
shift it to the right for small work.
The reason for that is that the smaller
the diff, the easier it is to totally
regenerate the code and hold it all in
context. So, if you have really massive
work, you want to align beforehand
because fixing it is really expensive
when you get to a later stage. So,
that's the theory. For big work, you
shift the review left. For small work,
you shift the review right.